ILGWU. President's Office records, 5780/154
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Greater Blouse, Skirt and Undergarment Association, 1982 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Collective bargaining agreements, special notice, and comments on the exposure draft, "'Employers' Accounting for Pension."
- Local 10, 1983 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Correspondence, memos, notes, comments, and memorandums.
- Atlantic Apparel, 1983 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  Correspondence, a copy of a newspaper article, and a newspaper ad clipping.
- Wilbur Daniels, 1983 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  Incoming and outgoing correspondence to and from Wilbur Daniels. Includes a page of a magazine.
- Irwin Solomon, 1983 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  Incoming and outgoing correspondence to and from Irwin Solomon.
- Japan, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  Reports on imports, facts and statistic, incoming and outgoing correspondence to and from Zensen, and handwritten notes.
- Judy Wineman, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  About Margarita Rodriguez.
- Retiree Service Department [Part 1 of 3], 1985 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  Concerning activities and expenses.
- Retiree Service Department [Part 2 of 3], 1982 - 1983 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  On-going activities and other reports.
- Retiree Service Department [Part 3 of 3], 1984 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  Expenses and reports.
- Union Health Center [Part 1 of 2], 1984 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  Hiring a medical director, other questions, and a report for the Union Health Center Committee.
- Union Health Center [Part 2 of 2], 1982 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  Memorandums, reports, and correspondence.
- Union Health Center Retirement, 1982 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  Amendments, reports, plans, and summaries.
- Union Label Department, 1983 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  Correspondence and memos. Includes a plastic bag made by Chicago Organizing Bags.
- Welfare Fund Control Department, 1984 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  Import bills.
- Sidney Vyorst, 1981 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  Correspondence, statements, reports, insurance programs, and agreements.
- Xerox, 1983 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  Brochures and a handbook.
- Employee Ownership, 1983 - 1985 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  Worker Ownership. Correspondence. Includes a handbook and a conference report.
- The Productivity Forum, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  Includes a report, a new policy study entitled "Training for New Technology, and other correspondence,
- Workplace Health Fund, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  Grant proposal.
- Women's Wear Daily [Part 1 of 2], 1985 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Copies of newspaper clippings.
- Women's Wear Daily [Part 2 of 2], 1983 - 1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Newspapers and copies of newspaper clippings.
- 1010 Wins Radio, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  A folder containing transcripts and a compact cassette about the recent Regional Affairs Council series, "The Big Battle of Small Business."
- Emanuel Weintraub Associates, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Correspondence and a draft proposal.
- WEVD Radio Station, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Grace Volckhausen, 1984 - 1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Correspondence from Grace Volckhausen, about her, and a copy of the Korea Times New York.
- Worker's Defense League, 1982 - 1983 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  45th Anniversary Celebration
- Roger Waldinger [Part 1 of 2], 1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Three reports: "Labor Law Under the Reagan Administration," "The Impact of Real Estate Market Trends on the Garment District," and "The Future Without the Project."
- Roger Waldinger [Part 2 of 2], 1984 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  Four more reports: "The Impact of the 42nd Street Redevelopment Project on the Garment Industry," "Testimony on the Final Environmental Impact Statement for the 42nd Street Development Project," "42nd Street Project: Preliminary Report #2," and "The Occupational and Economic Integration of New Immigrants."
- Unity House, 1983 - 1985 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  Includes invitations, minutes, and financial statements.
- United Nations Office for Emergency Operation in Africa, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  Status reports and correspondence.
- Union Sanatorium Association, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  Financial statements and photocopies of checks.
- Speech Unemployment, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  Newspaper entitled, "Federationist."
- Urban Development Corporation Hearing, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  42nd Street Redevelopment Project.
- Trade, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  Copies of articles, correspondence, and part of a newspaper.
- Alan Tobias, 1983 - 1985 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  Correspondence with Alan Tobias of Creative Developments concerning film.
- Textile Agreements, 1981 - 1983 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  Bilateral Textile Agreements.
- Textile and Apparel Trade Agreement Act [Part 1 of 2], 1985 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  Correspondence, vetoes, bills, and roll calls.
- Textile and Apparel Trade Agreement Act [Part 1 of 2], 1985 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  Correspondence and reports.
- Sweatshops, 1983 - 1985 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  Newspaper clippings.
- Anti-Sweatshops, 1981 - 1985 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  Correspondence about bills and legislation.
- Franz Leichter, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  Concerning sweatshops. This folder includes reports, newspaper clippings, hand-written notes, and statements.
- Statue of Liberty, 1984 - 1985 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  Correspondence and a brochure.
- Strike Benefits, 1984 - 1985 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  Regarding strike benefits.
- Subcommittee on Census and Population, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  Mailing list and a statement by Jay Mazur.
- Sub-Minimum Wage, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  Correspondence and an article by Sol C. Chaikin and Phil Comstock entitled, "Subminimum Wage: Sub-Par Idea."
- Sweatshop Bill, 1984 - 1985 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  Includes a copy of the bill and anti-sweatshop legislation. Also includes a Spanish language newspaper.
- The Stratford Advisory Group [Part 1 of 3], 1983 - 1985 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  A report entitled, "The Legitimacy of Directed 'Soft Dollars': An Analysis of the Current Controversy," and correspondence.
- The Stratford Advisory Group [Part 2 of 3], 1983 - 1985 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  A copy of the "Master Custodian Questionnaire," a proposed timetable, an article, and correspondence regarding various matters.
- The Stratford Advisory Group [Part 3 of 3], 1983 - 1985 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  Reports entitled, "Consolidation of Assets," "Developing an Investment Policy Statement," "A Suggested Approach to More Effective Management of ILGWU General Funds and Trust Funds," and "COMPARE--COMParative Performance Analysis and Review". Other documents are correspondence and 1983 market performance table.
- Statue of Liberty Centennial Commission, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  Regarding multi-cultural events, festivals, and exhibitions.
- Statue of Liberty Financial Committee, 1983 - 1985 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  Articles and finances for upcoming projects, such as the centennial.
- Simpson-Mazzoli Bill, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  A copy of Jay Mazur's testimony about the bill, an article, and a report from the National Immigration, Refugee, and Citizenship Forum.
- Victor Riesel, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  "After 100 Years, Labors Newest Strategy," an article by Riesel.
- Arthur Silverstein, 1983 - 1985 (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Sportswear Employers Convention, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  Points from the convention.
- Resolution – Investment Assets, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Documents regarding authorizations.
- Regional Plan Association [Part 1 of 2], 1983 - 1985 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  Nominating Committee. Includes memorandums and agendas.
- Regional Plan Association [Part 2 of 2], 1985 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  Transportation.
- Paul Segal Associates, 1983 - 1984 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  Finances.
- Roundabout, 1984 - 1985 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  A theater company. Includes correspondence, an invitation, newspaper articles, and a brochure.
- Resumes [Part 1 of 2], 1983 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Resumes [Part 2 of 2], 1984 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Resumes [Part 3 of 3], 1985 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Francois Sauzey, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  Correspondence from Francois Sauzey, the future of the AFL-CIO's foreign policy, memo, and a resume.
- Africa Seminar, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  Outline and transcript from seminar, receipts, and a status report from the United Nations.
- Office Expenses, 1983 - 1985 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  Receipts and correspondence about finances.
- Organization for Rehabilitation through Training, 1984 - 1986 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Occupational Safety and Health Administration, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  ILGWU's revised budget and work plan for the Third Developmental Year.
- Occupational Health Legal Rights Foundation, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  Six month reports and a prospectus.
- Negotiations, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  Articles and correspondence from various organizations.
- Noel Arnold Levin, 1984 - 1985 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  Correspondence, memorandums, and a copy of Textile Workers Pension Fund v. Standard Dye and Finishing Co., Inc., et al.
- League for Industrial Democracy, 1983 - 1985 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  Correspondence and a Foreign Affairs Report entitled, "Are Things Getting Better in Eastern Europe?"
- U.S. Used and Leased Cars [Part 1 of 4], 1984 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  From these following regions: New Jersey; New England; Midwest; Northeast, Western Pennsylvania, and Ohio; Central States.
- U.S. Used and Leased Cars [Part 2 of 4], 1984 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  From these following regions: New York City; Southeastern States; Western States.
- U.S. Used and Leased Cars [Part 3 of 4], 1984 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  From the Upper South region.
- U.S. Used and Leased Cars [Part 4 of 4], 1984 - 1985 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  Correspondence from various regional departments.
- Leader Data Processing, 1983 - 1985 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  Memorandum and correspondence about an employee named Joe Walsh, a report entitled "Data Center Understanding Between ILGWU & LDP", and a proposal.
- The Labor Theater, 1984 - 1985 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  List of contributors and ticket purchasers, and a tribute to Howard Molisani.
- Regional Plan Association [Part 1 of 5], 1984 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  "New York in the Global Economy" proposal and the Jamaica Project Committee
- Regional Plan Association [Part 2 of 5], 1983 - 1985 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  News releases and documents regarding executive committee meetings.
- Regional Plan Association [Part 3 of 5], 1983 - 1985 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  Regarding the development of 42nd street.
- Regional Plan Association [Part 4 of 5], 1983 - 1985 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Regional Plan Association [Part 5 of 5], 1983 - 1984 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  New Jersey Committee.
- Progression Increases, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  Comparison of Progression Increases: present versus various options.
- Asian-American Free Labor Institute (AAFLI), 1984 - 1985 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, reports on Asian-American worker attitudes towards unions and Australia, and a copy of the bi-monthly magazine entitled, "Asia Labor Monitor".
- Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU), 1985 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- American Fiber, Textile, and Apparel Coalition (AFTAC), 1983 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  Recommendations to the White House working group on textiles by the executive committee.
- AFL-CIO [Part 1 of 4], 1983 - 1984 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  Includes the newsletter entitled, "Free Trade Union News," a Presidential candidate analysis entitled, "Mondale and Ferraro versus Reagan and Bush," 1984 AFL-CIO Platform proposals, Black labor, and other memorandums and correspondence.
- AFL-CIO [Part 2 of 4], 1983 - 1984 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- AFL-CIO [Part 3 of 4], 1985 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  Speech transcript, "Convention News" newsletters, a report entitled, "Economic Notes", and general correspondence.
- AFL-CIO [Part 4 of 4], 1985 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  A report entitled, "The Changing Situation of Workers and Their Unions." Includes a copy of the "Federationist" newspaper.
- AFTAC Executive Meeting, 1982 - 1984 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  Includes an agenda and key points of the 1984 meeting, a U.S. textile and apparel import market disruption report, international statistics, a newspaper article, press release, and a statement entitled, "Exchange Rates and International Trade."
- Amal, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  Network of the General Federation of Labor in Israel. Includes educational pamphlets, posters, a report, and correspondence.
- American Arbitration Association, 1984 - 1985 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  Agenda and minutes of the labor section of the Arbitration Practice Committee, correspondence, notes, and a transcript of a statement by Jay Mazur.
- Blue Cross/Blue Shield, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  Hospital and medical costs and a study of The Local 23-25 Health and Welfare Fund.
- Labor in China, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  Report entitled, "After Mao: Is Deng Liberating China's Workers?" and a schedule of the Executive Education Institute.
- Brooklyn, 1983 - 1984 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  Project summary, photocopies of news articles, and a report from the U.S. Department of Labor's Employment Standards Administration, Wage Hour Division.
- Board of Industrial Appeals, 1976 - 1984 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  Concerning hiring, and includes resumes, biographies, correspondence, and copies of newspaper clippings.
- Campaign Committee [Part 1 of 4], 1985 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  Contributions and collections.
- Campaign Committee [Part 2 of 4], 1985 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  Contributions, collections, and fund raising.
- Campaign Committee [Part 3 of 4], 1984 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  Contributions.
- Campaign Committee [Part 4 of 4], 1984 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Census Comparison, 1982 - 1985 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  Comparison of memberships across all regions and states.
- Canadian Labor Congress, 1982 - 1984 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Chaikin and Chaikin, 1983 - 1985 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  Finances, bills, a copy of a restraining order, and handwritten notes.
- Chinatown Garment Industry [Part 1 of 2], 1982 - 1985 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  An overview of Chinatown's garment industry, a New York Affairs report entitled, "Uneven Change", a press release regarding the commencement of a Chinatown nursery school, support for a text change in a law, essays entitled, "Immigrants and Entrepreneurs"
- Chinatown Garment Industry [Part 2 of 2], 1982 - 1985 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  Correspondence, agendas, drafts of the overview of Chinatown Garment Industry studies, remarks by President Chaikin, and the Chung Pak Project.
- Chinatown, 1983 - 1985 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  News clippings and a transcript of a speech by Jay Mazur.
- Cuban-Haitian Adjustment Act of 1984, 1983 - 1984 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  Statements by Jay Mazur and Honorable Peter W. Rodino Jr., the act, and facts about it.
- Commission on the Year 2000, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  Testimonies.
- Commercial Rent Control, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  Testimonies, statements, and a hearing. Includes a copy of a newspaper article.
- Clough and Associates, 1984 - 1985 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  Correspondence and thoughts on using computers.
- Chung Park, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  Project plan, general leasing, fact sheet, and resolutions.
- Chishti, Muzaffar, 1984 - 1985 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  Local 23-25 Immigration Project, Occasional Reports to the Manager.
- Coalition for a Democratic Majority, 1983 - 1985 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  Correspondence, memorandums, and a proposal entitled, "Democratic Solidarity."
- Coalition of Labor Union Women, 1984 - 1985 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  Regarding a new public relations campaign and national membership drive, correspondence, memorandums, and finances.
- Contributions - Requests - Acknowledgements [Part 1 of 4], 1983 - 1984 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Contributions - Requests - Acknowledgements [Part 2 of 4], 1983 - 1984 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Contributions - Requests - Acknowledgements [Part 3 of 4], 1985 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Contributions - Requests - Acknowledgements [Part 4 of 4], 1983 - 1985 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Institute for Education and Research on Women and Work, 1984 - 1985 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Correspondence Log, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Susan Cowell, 1984 - 1985 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  Concerning former ILGWU members, childcare, Statue of Liberty Celebrations, questionnaire, proposed retention program, memorandums, and correspondence.
- City University of New York, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  Concerning College-Wide Advisory Council. Includes pamphlets and brochures.
- Democratic Socialists of America, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  Trade unionist meeting, an appeal, the Democratic Left, an order form, and "Social Benefits and the U.S. Worker."
- Economic Policy Council [Part 1 of 3], 1984 - 1986 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  Agendas, statements, updates, activity reports, a report entitled, "Preliminary Notes on the Economic Strategy of the New Brazilian Government," and general correspondence.
- Economic Policy Council [Part 2 of 3], 1984 - 1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  Meeting notes, handwritten notes, newspaper clippings, Text and Apparel Trade Enforcement Act of 1985 Fact Sheet, World Financial Markets newsletter, reports and articles concerning Brazil, and a report entitled, "Trade Strategy and Industrial Policy in T
- Economic Policy Council [Part 3 of 3], 1984 - 1986 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  Response to Trade Strategy and Industrial Policy of Taiwan, an agenda, major economic indicators tables, imports from Korea, and a report from the Economic Policy Council entitled, "The Global Repercussions of US Monetary and Fiscal Policy."
- Fiber, Fabric, and Apparel Coalition for Trade (FFACT) [Part 1 of 2], 1984 - 1985 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  A report entitled, "Trade Strategy and Industrial Policy in Taiwan," correspondence regarding the Arrangement Regarding International Trade in Textiles, Textile and Apparel Trade Enforcement Act, confidential documents, and a statement of John N. Gregg.
- Fiber, Fabric, and Apparel Coalition for Trade (FFACT) [Part 2 of 2], 1984 - 1985 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  NYC Apparel Industry Fact Sheet, Roll Back Imports, updates, "Stop Unfair Imports" packets, copies of newspaper clippings, and a statement of Sol C. Chaikin.
- Expenses [Part 1 of 2], 1983 - 1985 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  Credit Card Expenses.
- Expenses [Part 2 of 2], 1983 - 1985 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  Florist, Restaurant, and miscellaneous expenses.
- Ethiopia Relief Fund, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  Collections, Ethiopian Jewish Rescue Effort, and Ethiopian food relief.
- Environmental Protection Committee, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  Regarding cancer causing asbestos.
- Employers Meeting, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  Points for presentation at the Sportswear employers' convention and handwritten notes.
- Employer Manual, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  A human resource management newsletter in preparation for the creation of a manual of Employee fringe benefits and insurance coverage.
- Employee Stock Ownership Plan (ESOP), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  Two articles. One is entitled, "ESOPs: Revolution or Rip-off?" and the other is called, "Blue-Collar Boardrooms."
- Election '84, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  Election schedule and documents regarding voting.
- 42nd Street Project [Part 1 of 2], 1984 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  Newspaper clippings, meeting points, street merchandise mart, a testimony, summary, and correspondence.
- 42nd Street Project [Part 2 of 2], 1984 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  Channel 2, Channel 4, Speech, and joint statement.
- Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  Correspondence, speech, pamphlet.
- Federacion Interamericana de Trabajadores de la Industria Textil, Vestuario, Cuero y Calzado (FITITVC), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  List of executive committee members, executive directors, and deputies.
- NY Times Interview, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  Regarding 42nd Street Redevelopment Project.
- Federal Election Commission, 1984 - 1985 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  Reporting notice for monthly filers and a complaint that Jay Mazur and company violated the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971.
- 42nd Street Testimony [Part 1 of 4], 1984 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  Environmental Impact Statements.
- 42nd Street Testimony [Part 2 of 4], 1984 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  Speeches, outline and summary of testimony, and comments on the environmental impact statement.
- 42nd Street Testimony [Part 3 of 4], 1984 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  Speeches, summaries, and comments.
- 42nd Street Testimony [Part 4 of 4], 1984 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  Statements, comments, speeches, and summaries.
- Board of Estimate Testimony and Barney's Expansion, 1984 - 1985 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  Statements made by Jay Mazur.